ALLAN OGWANG

Berkeley, CA ◆ ogwang@berkeley.edu

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am intrigued by the vast applications of Civil Engineering research in the world around us. As a graduate student in Civil Engineering, an opportunity to display my well-learned skills in Civil Engineering and Infrastructure Management would be a dream come true.

SKILLS

- Excellent attention to detail
- Fast learner
- Project Management
- Professional Communication skills
- Programming in Matlab, R, and Python
- Statistical Data Analysis
- Software: GIS, AutoCAD, MS Project
- Performance optimization

WORK HISTORY

Junior Transportation Engineer, 06/2013 to 11/2013

DKS Associates - Oakland, CA

- Evaluated traffic control devices and lighting systems to determine need for modification and expansion for the Oakland BRT project.
- Planned alteration of existing road alignment in Oregon State to improve safety and function.
- Prepared final project layout drawings that included details such as lighting specifications, traffic control devices and their respective locations.

Graduate Student Researcher, 08/2012 to 05/2013

University of California at Berkeley – Berkeley, CA

- Carried out research on the feasibility of using the Bay Area Rapid Transit (BART) system for Air-Freight movement.
- I performed data analysis to determine schedule modification which would allow freight train(s) insertions.
- Explored the environmental burden attributed to freight transportation in terms of global warming potential (GWP).

Project Engineer, 11/2011 to 03/2012

Bremen Overseas Research and Development Association (BORDA) - Dar-es-Salaam, TZ

- Analyzed and recommended Biogas treatment plants for rural communities.
- Oversaw the construction of decentralized and on-site wastewater treatment systems, including reclaimed water facilities.
- Provided technical direction and made computer-aided design (CAD) drawings for the decentralized treatment plants and Biogas facilities

EDUCATION

Ph.D.: Civil and Environmental Engineering, Current

University of California at Berkeley - Berkeley, CA

• Emphasis in Pavement Infrastructure Systems Management and Policy Evaluation for a Sustainable Environment with a concentration in Asphalt Pavements

Master of Science: Civil and Environmental Engineering, 2013

University of California at Berkeley - Berkeley, CA

• Transportation Engineering Program

Bachelor of Science: Civil and Transportation Engineering, 2011

University of Dar-es-Salaam - Dar-es-Salaam, TZ

- Project: A comparative Analysis of Bus Rapid Transit (BRT) and Light Rail Transit (LRT) for public transport in Dar-es-Salam
- Best Final Year Project in the Department of Transportation Engineering
- Best Undergraduate Civil Engineering Student
- Best student in courses offered by the Construction Technology and Management Department

AFFILIATIONS

- American Society of Civil Engineers (ASCE): Membership ID 10143187
- Young Professionals in Transportation (YPT): San Francisco Bay Chapter
- SmileyGo: Connecting the World and Creating Smiles

CREDENTIALS -

• Engineer in Training (EIT): Certification ID - 1448995